savoryexperiments.com 2019-08-19

# Privacy Policy | Savory Experiments

_Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website._

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what “personally identifiable information” (PII) we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to www.savoryexperiments.com.

### We may use the information collected in the following ways:

  * To operate and maintain the Website and create a better user experience;
  * To track trends and analytics for administrator usage;
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings (information is voluntarily provided);
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries;
  * To provide you with user support;
  * To track and measure advertising on the Website;
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

### What information do we collect and how do we use it?

**Information you voluntarily submit to our website:**  
We may collect PII such as name or email address when you sign up for our newsletter, leave a comment or complete a contact form.

**Automatically Collected Information:**  
Like most websites, we collect basic PII and the device you use to access our Website. For example, when you visit our website, it logs your IP address, location, operating system, referring website, pages you viewed, dates and times accessed and type of device you used to access. We may also collect information on the information you view while here, such as links you click on.

**Cookies:**  
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyze web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

Like most websites, we use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about webpage traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you voluntarily choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can modify your browser setting to decline cookies, if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

**Advertising:**  
Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers, although if you’ve updated your personal web browser settings, this should prevent them from being seen.

We use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the Website, including MediaVine. These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data.

The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and Savory Experiments disclaims all liability in connection therewith.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/).

_Display Ads:_  
We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies, as noted above.

_Retargeting Ads:_  
From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

### Third Party Use of PII:

We may share your information with third parties when you _explicitly_ authorize us to share your information. An example of this would be if you won a giveaway and w provided your shipping address to the company sending you the prize.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies

The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

_Google Analytics_ – this service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.

_ActiveCampaign_ – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications. Please refer to [ActiveCampaign’s privacy policy](https://www.activecampaign.com/privacy-policy/) for further information.

### Anonymous Data:

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or demographic information collected from cookies. An example would be the Website telling a third party that the majority of it’s viewers are female or located in the United States.

### Publicly Visible Information:

If you leave a comment, certain information may be publicly visible, such as an avatar you have connected to your email. Your email address will never be available publicly.

### Affiliate Program Participation:

The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

Savory Experiments is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.

As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

### Newsletters:

On the Website, you may voluntarily subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for communication or advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. We will NEVER sell our mail list to any third parties. You may unsubscribe at any time.

### Rights Related to Your Personal Data:

Opt-out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at jessica@savoryexperiments.com to be removed from our mailing list.

Access – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to jessica@savoryexperiments.com.

Amend – You may contact us at jessica@savoryexperiments.com to amend or update your personal information.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to jessica@savoryexperiments.com.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law. None of this PII would personally identify you.

### Sensitive Personal Information:

We will NEVER ask you to submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, credit card information, bank information or trade union memberships.

### Children’s Information:

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at jessica@savoryexperiments.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

### Family Friendly Content:

We can not control children from visiting our page. We aim to make sure all information on our Website is family friendly and does not contain lewd, provocative or otherwise offensive materials. If you do see something you find offensive, please contact us immediately.

### Security:

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. Savory Experiments has an active SSL certificate and several safeguards in place to prevent this from happening.

### Disclosure Policy

This blog is a personal blog written and edited by Jessica Formicola. For questions about this blog, please contact savoryexperiment@gmail.com. This blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions or other forms of compensation. The compensation received will never influence the content, topics or posts made in this blog. All advertising is in the form of advertisements generated by a third party ad network. Those advertisements will be identified as paid advertisements. The owner(s) of this blog is compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though the owner(s) of this blog receives compensation for our posts or advertisements, we always give our honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the bloggers’ own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

This blog does not contain any content which might present a conflict of interest.

### Contact Information:

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, or you have questions regarding our privacy  please contact us at jessica@savoryexperiments.com.

Last updated: May 17, 2018.
